<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blogging on Curious Cyrus</title>
    <link>https://curiouscyrus.me/tags/blogging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blogging on Curious Cyrus</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© Cyrus Sowdaey; MIT License</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 11:51:55 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://curiouscyrus.me/tags/blogging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Constructing the Test and Development Environment</title>
      <link>https://curiouscyrus.me/post/paludariumdevenvironment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 11:51:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://curiouscyrus.me/post/paludariumdevenvironment/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Introduction: Creating a dedicated test and development environment for in-development sensors and systems is crucial to avoid risks to your larger ecosystem when adding new features or testing changes. In this blog post, I&#39;ll take you through the step-by-step process of constructing a small 12 x 12 Paludarium with a spray-bar for effective testing and development.
Acquiring the Materials Here are the main materials I used when constructing this simple background
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing LEAP&#39;s Early Systems Architecture</title>
      <link>https://curiouscyrus.me/post/earlysystemsdesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 11:51:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://curiouscyrus.me/post/earlysystemsdesign/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            What does Early Systems Diagramming look like?: In the realm of technology and software + hardware development, this process involves creating the initial diagrams for the main system and its encompassed subsystems! These diagrams have been created from my earlier post involving the Brainstorming of LEAP
Further, I&#39;d like to also delve into the significance of this phase and explore the facets involved in developing this evolving blueprint that will guide the rest of the development journey.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brainstorming LEAP&#39;s Features</title>
      <link>https://curiouscyrus.me/post/brainstorming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 15:51:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://curiouscyrus.me/post/brainstorming/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Intro - Defining Components of LEAP: This post details the process I went through while working on the initial planning of the Paludarium, to organize and sort the possible scope of the Living Ecosystem Automation Project.
This was one of the first times I used a Mind map, but I found it to help sort some ideas I had previously written down, but did not have collected in any meaningful matter to share.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trials and Tribulations of Website Hosting</title>
      <link>https://curiouscyrus.me/post/trials-and-tribulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 15:51:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://curiouscyrus.me/post/trials-and-tribulations/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Info:This post details the process I went through while working on this Blog website and ultimately hosting it here at https://curiouscyrus.me/
For more information on why this blog exists, and the content on it, see What is LEAP? You can also find the accompanying public repository for my Web app here as well!
Deciding on the Type of Website One of the first steps on my Website creation adventure was to determine the type of website that would be suited for my specific application.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When an idea becomes a plan, then a plan becomes action</title>
      <link>https://curiouscyrus.me/post/leaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 15:51:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://curiouscyrus.me/post/leaps/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            Documenting a New Project: Hey there, and welcome to the first blog post on Automation and Curiosities! I&#39;ve created this Website as a way to share my continued progress, experiences (good or bad), and knowledge gained while working on Automating the World!
Well, to be specific, the scope is actually the wonderful &amp;quot;World&amp;quot; of simulated ecosystems and environments!
One of my main goals with these types of posts and the content I create is to both provide knowledge to others, as well as show some of the problems I have run into, while cataloguing and providing visual supplements that aid in understanding!
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LEAP - A new initiative</title>
      <link>https://curiouscyrus.me/post/starting-a-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 15:51:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://curiouscyrus.me/post/starting-a-project/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
            So, what exactly is this?? LEAP - Living Ecosystem Automation Project LEAP is a project I have been slowly building a plan together for since as early as 09/26/2023 when looking to incorporate water and land elements in a living ecosystem, after becoming inspired by some excellently designed enclosures that other hobbyists have designed in recent years.
Eventually, this morphed into something where I wanted to combine my skills and knowledge in Embedded Systems design with a goal of creating multiple subsystems run by specialized microcontrollers, which could vary between irrigation controls, livestreamed camera feed, humidity tracking, and much more.
          
          
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
